Romain Giovanetti

+33 6 09 03 42 27

n giovanetti.fr

Profile

Full-Stack Designer with nine years of international experiences in designing, developing, and maintaining apps.

Creative and curious, I value quality no matter what I am making.

I like in particular **web technologies**, and I'm focused on continually improving the **user experience**.

Main Skills

Fields

Critical thinking, User Experience, Software Architecture, Design, Web Services, Data Mining, and Problem Solving.

Technologies

Symfony, React, Java EE, Node.js, RESTFul APIs, Elasticsearch, Python, MySQL, Redux, SASS, Oracle, SOAP, and Express.

Languages

French • • • • • English • • • • O German • • O O O

Experience

Full-Stack Designer

December 2019 Present Freelance, Saint Memmie, France

- Designed and implemented a custom made system to automatically generate and send quotes (as PDFs) to La Maison De L'Eleveur's customers;
- Designed and built several custom product assistants for the website of La Maison De L'Eleveur, to ease the purchase of configurable products;
- Designed and implemented custom product pricing modules for the website of La Maison De L'Eleveur, to compute dynamic prices based on the configuration of configurable products;
- Added several tests classes to the website of La Maison De L'Eleveur, to avoid regressions;
- Refactored and migrated to Symfony 4 the website of La Maison De L'Eleveur;
- Designed and implemented a custom order system for the website of La Maison De L'Eleveur;
- Designed and built the website of Champagne Carole Haudot, including a small online shop, using React + Redux.

May 2018 November 2019

Software Developer

Coface North America, Princeton, NJ, United States of America

★ V.I.E. (International Volunteer in Business) in the USA (New York)

- Maintained policy management applications and collection back office support applications (back-end and front-end);
- Participated in solution architecture and design;
- Designed and developed interfaces to facilitate communication between different software applications;
- Created debug tools related to PDF generation;
- Updated the DEV wiki;
- Maintained legacy code and refactored it when it was possible;
- ▼ Following a penetration test, reinforced the security of the main application and its side apps, including a password encryption upgrade, and a complete rework of the "I forgot my password" process.
- Blog about this amazing part of my life: vie-usa.giovanetti.fr

September 2017 April 2018

Full-Stack Designer

Freelance, Saint Memmie, France

- Started my own small company in France;
- ✓ Migrated the website of La Maison De L'Eleveur to Symfony 3;
- ✓ Introduced new features to the website of La Maison De L'Eleveur, using various web technologies (Symfony 2/3, MySQL, Bootstrap, Javascript...).

October 2014 August 2017

Research Engineer

CNRS / Université de Lille / CRIStAL Lab. / NOCE Team, Lille, France

- Published two publications in the IEEE international conference on Advances in Social Network Analysis and Mining 2016 (ASONAM);
- Built a distributed platform for collecting and processing billions of tweets, powered by Elasticsearch and TensorFlow;
- Created a fast, beautiful and easy to use dashboard, made possible by a complete asynchronous stack featuring AngularJS and Node.js;
- Designed methods to extract sentiments, gender and geolocation from very small texts (tweets) using recursive neural networks.

June 2014 September 2014

Research Engineer

La Maison De L'Eleveur, Vouziers, France

- Revamped the online catalogue (more than 1500 references);
- Rebuilt from scratch the e-commerce website, within 3 months, using Symfony 2, Bootstrap and jQuery;
- Prototyped and implemented an easy to use user interfaces to ease the purchase of steel sheets;
- Deployed the new website, maintained it, and improved it according to customer feedback;
- The greatly enhanced customer experience led to an increase of sales.

March 2013 February 2014

Research Engineer

CNRS / Université de Lille / CRIStAL Lab. / NOCE Team, Lille, France

- Designed and built custom made bracelets that communicated with each other, using Arduino nano, Xbee modules, batteries, handmade housings, vibrators, RFID chips, and other small components;
- Designed and built custom made contactless quiz terminals, using Arduino mega, ethernet shields, RFID shields, and other small components;
- Created a main control system (Java + MongoDB) to remotely manage and configure the custom made devices, and log their usages;
- Built a dashboard (Node.js + Express + MongoDB) to filter the collected usages data and present them in a meaningful way;
- Deployed the custom made devices and the main control system in the Museum of Fine Arts of Tourcoing, France, and conducted user experience evaluations.



Discover more experiences and side projects on giovanetti.fr/resume

Education Master's Degree in Computer Science

Université de Lille, France - September 2013

rasmus semester at the Technische Universität Graz in Austria.

References

Available upon request.

Links

- ngiovanetti.fr
- github.com/ganoninc
- in linkedin.com/in/romainjg
- 🖹 stackoverflow.com/users/2815175/r-giovanetti

EU-AU-2022-05-12 Page 3 of 3